<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pages on My Elixir Diary</title>
    <link>http://elixir-diary.mafinar.com/pages/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Pages on My Elixir Diary</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2016 19:11:37 +0600</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://elixir-diary.mafinar.com/pages/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Links</title>
      <link>http://elixir-diary.mafinar.com/pages/links/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2016 19:11:37 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://elixir-diary.mafinar.com/pages/links/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is where I place all the links that helped my during my exploration of Elixir.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://elixir-lang.org/&#34;&gt;Elixir Homepage&lt;/a&gt; These guys have really good documentation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/elixir&#34;&gt;/r/elixir/&lt;/a&gt; The subreddit dedicated to Elixir&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/niftyn8/elixir_style_guide&#34;&gt;Elixir Style Guide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/h4cc/awesome-elixir&#34;&gt;Awesome Elixir&lt;/a&gt; This is what makes this link redundant.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will keep this link updated with whatever I find during the course of time :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Me</title>
      <link>http://elixir-diary.mafinar.com/pages/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2016 19:11:37 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://elixir-diary.mafinar.com/pages/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mafinar Khan&lt;/strong&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;m the Product Manager at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bdpanacea.com&#34;&gt;Panacea Systems Ltd&lt;/a&gt; where I help build stuff. I work with Python (❤ Django), ClojureScript and TypeScript (❤ Mobx). I&amp;rsquo;m learning Elixir nowadays which is why this site exists.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am an annoying husband to a very tolerant lady and a cool dad of a handsome 22 month old (As of June 2016).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My Twitters down there in the footer.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meta</title>
      <link>http://elixir-diary.mafinar.com/pages/meta/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2016 19:11:37 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://elixir-diary.mafinar.com/pages/meta/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;This page was generated by the awesome static site generator &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt;. I stole the awesome &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/digitalcraftsman/hugo-steam-theme&#34;&gt;Steam&lt;/a&gt; and modified it a little by adding my favorite fonts: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.google.com/fonts#UsePlace:use/Collection:Oswald&#34;&gt;Oswald&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.google.com/fonts#UsePlace:use/Collection:Abel&#34;&gt;Abel&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.google.com/fonts#UsePlace:use/Collection:Dosis&#34;&gt;Dosis&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.google.com/fonts#UsePlace:use/Collection:Source+Code+Pro&#34;&gt;Source Code Pro&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt; HEAD&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-source-code-can-be-found-here-https-github-com-code-shoily-elixir-diary-src&#34;&gt;The source code can be found &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/code-shoily/elixir-diary-src&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The source code can be found &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/code-shoily/my-elixir-diary&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;
&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; fcce313fe6b1fdcbd1023355445a0c8b21967520&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I somehow survive this, I intend to go Phoenix and do something like &lt;strong&gt;Phoenix Chronicles&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This</title>
      <link>http://elixir-diary.mafinar.com/pages/hello/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2016 19:11:37 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://elixir-diary.mafinar.com/pages/hello/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After admiring Elixir from a distance for a while, I&amp;rsquo;m finally learning it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love collecting programming languages. Python was the first language I learnt on my own, back in school. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t taught there, no assignments or grade points were attached with it, and it was fun. I still remember the whoa-s I had when I first discovered the REPL, dynamic typing, and regular expressions. Since then I kept an open mind about new programming languages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing I noticed is, the more languages I get acquinted with, the more &lt;em&gt;questions&lt;/em&gt; I learn to ask when learning a new one (i.e. &lt;em&gt;How does the else-if look like here?&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;How do I define a anonymous function?&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Does it have pattern matching?&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Wait, no exception handling?&lt;/em&gt;). I &lt;strong&gt;do&lt;/strong&gt; make a note of emptying my cup though, there&amp;rsquo;s no fun learning a new language if you don&amp;rsquo;t start with the immortal &lt;code&gt;Hello World&lt;/code&gt;. So I end up writing some codes, talking with my peers about it, making things with it, sneaking it at my work place, or just leaving it with a &lt;em&gt;sigh&lt;/em&gt;. I think it would be fun writing my experiences &lt;em&gt;while&lt;/em&gt; I&amp;rsquo;m learning a language and the cup is still empty: raw thoughts, raw codes, lots of bloopers!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I tend to pick on one language a year. This year, I picked Go. A nifty little language that reminded me back of the school days. Then I stumbled upon a reddit post that was talking about Elixir and the people and their comments seemed nice. So I checked the homepage and read up. Installed and coded &lt;code&gt;1+1&lt;/code&gt; too. I loved it how Elixir made me think. So after wasting a few weeks just reading up, this Friday I decided I&amp;rsquo;d break the one language per year rule and just get started with Elixir, and for what&amp;rsquo;s written on the previous paragraph, &lt;strong&gt;Write about it too&lt;/strong&gt;. Nothing fancy or sophisticated though, I&amp;rsquo;ll just fire up the shell, open an editor, the manual, and write whatever emotions I&amp;rsquo;m getting hit with. I&amp;rsquo;m sure I&amp;rsquo;ll come back here and laugh about it in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s hope I don&amp;rsquo;t laugh too much though.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>